Alecs Sandra Saminathan

alecs.sandra@outlook.com| +447990156603 | www.linkedin.com/in/alecssandra | Birmingham, UK

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Performance driven Digital Marketing Manager with 9+ years' experience in Digital Marketing, Client Relations, Project Management, Customer Service and Team Leadership. Proven success in advertising and conversion optimisations. Delivered **\$12.8M** in revenue within 14 days, Achieved **400%** ROAS through strategic campaign optimizations on social media.

EDUCATION

MSc in Marketing | University of Worcester | 2023 - 2024

• Modules: Marketing Management, Marketing Communications, Corporate Entrepreneurship

BA Mass Communication | St. Francis College for Women | 2013 – 2016

• Modules: Public Relations, Mass Communication, English Literature

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital Marketing and E-commerce Manager | Home Linens Retail Group | October 2023 – Current | Birmingham, UK

- Scaled ROAS from 300% to 500% through ad group restructuring, creatives refresh and budget optimization
- Managed performance campaigns across Google, Bing and other social media channels
- Drove 23% AOV and scaled to 40% by leading website redesign project and adding variation logic on product page
- Developed and managed a team of +3 alongside external agencies and freelancers with effective bandwidth management
- Planned and presented data driven strategies to meet business goals with the Director

Senior Digital Marketing and Research Associate (Analyst - LCS) | Google Operations Centre | January 2021 - August 2023 | Hyderabad, India

- Worked with the largest advertising businesses across the AUNZ market to drive sustainable, profitable growth for client portfolios.
- Delivered \$12.8M in revenue within 14 days through precise Keyword targeting for a travel client
- Managed full stakeholder communications and task assignment for multi sector
- Collaborated with Account Managers and Sales Specialists for recurring projects
- Mentored +4 new hires and successfully helped transition from training to production

Sales Consultant (Account Strategist - SMB) | MarketStar India | May 2019 - December 2020 | Hyderabad, India

- Owned a portfolio of +200 clients by thoroughly understanding growth drivers, identifying opportunities for growth, managing risks, and building quarterly plans for achievement
- Conducted outbound consultations with advertisers to provide strategic recommendations for optimizing Google Ads performance
- Understanding client business goals and aligning Google's solutions to meet them

Customer Service Representative | Amazon.com | July 2017 - April 2019 | Hyderabad, India

- Trained **70**+ new hires, achieving a **96**% CSAT score through process improvements
- Awarded "Employee of the Year" for consistent performance and leadership skills

Customer Service Representative | Synchrony Financial | June 2016 – April 2017 | Hyderabad, India

- Resolved credit card, payment, and banking inquiries, exceeding consumer expectations with a 98% resolution rate
- Updated customer account information with 100% accuracy, improving data integrity and customer trust

LANGUAGES, SKILLS AND CERTIFICATES

- Languages: English, Hindi, Tamil
- Core Skills: Consultative Selling, Performance Marketing, Analytical Thinking, Translate to Business Value
- Tools: Google Ads, Google Analytics, SA360, Google Workspace, Microsoft Office
- Leadership: Project and Client Management, Time Management, Stakeholder Collaboration, Team Management
- Certifications: Google Search, Google Display, Google Video